C

(438) 792-2038



Montréal Under Permanent Residency



mickael.wajnberg@gmail.com



mickael-wajnberg

Skills

Algorithms

Data Analysis

Artificial Intelligence

Management

Communication

Ontologies

Languages

French

Native speaker

English

Fluent

Programming



SQL

SPARQL

Python

Mickaël Wajnberg

Ph.D. - Data Scientist & A.I./M.L. Scientist

During my double PhD, I specialized in Multi-Relational Data Mining with a strong portfolio of academic publications. After graduation, I've partnered with a startup, Softwords consulting, to commercialize my thesis algorithms. In parallel, I worked as a postdoctoral researcher on a new educational project on predictive maintenance. I also managed 5 research teams for student projects and consulted in AI with 6 clients from pro bono to commercial. Enthusiastic, social and positive, I'm looking forward working with brilliant minds to crack exciting problems.

Work Experience

Chief Research Officer Softwords Consulting

05/2021 - 12/2023

- Designed and developed the data mining engine in C++/SQL
- Acted as Co-C.P.O. to adapt product features fitting the market
- Collaborated on client prospection and marketing strategies
- Consulted at client's to provide data analysis and training

Postdoctoral Researcher

05/2021 - 02/2023

Université du Québec À Montréal - RTMQ

- Designed T.F. deep learning predictive maintenance models
- Developed a MERN Stack and GitLab (CI/CD) DevOps
- Managed a team of 5 interns

A.I. Consultant

12/2022 - Present

Freelance

- Tailored AI conferences/workshops to non-specialized audiance
- Edited and reviewed grant applications
- Guided startups in recommendation system design

Research Intern - MITACS Grant GoldFish Technologies

06/2015 - 10/2016

- Manipulated Ontologies and TripleStores with SPARQL
- Developed recommendation system on heterogenous data

Various Teaching Positions

06/2015 - 06/2023

- Course Lecturer UQAM: Introduction to programming
- Research supervisor Telecom Nancy : 5 teams of 2-3 students
- Teacher Assistant UQAM : Relational Databases
- Teacher Assistant UQAM : Artificial Intelligence
- Research co-supervisor Telecom Nancy : 1 team of 2 students
- Teacher Assistant Telecom Nancy : XML

Accomplishments

2023

Joined Mensa International

2018

Came in 2nd place for the hackathon HackQc by developing a web app that computes a score evaluating environmental aspect of any address in Montréal. Took into account number of trees, size of surrounding parks, water and air quality

2011-2012

Successfully managed a team of 100+ volunteers for an event of 4,500+ attendees at Anim'Est (a convention on japanese culture) as Head of Logistics and Human Resources

Interests

Sciences Teaching

Writing/Playing Music

Martial Arts Improv' Theater

Escape Games Chess

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science | 2020 UQAM (Canada) and Université de Lorraine (France)

- With Highest Honors and GPA: 4.3/4.3
- Specialty in Data Mining
- Joint supervision (cotutelle)

Masters in Computer Science | 2015 UQAC (Canada)

• Specialty in Metaheuristics - intership at Polytechnique

Masters in Computer Science Engineering | 2014 Télécom Nancy (France)

• Specialty in Algorithms and Data Structures

Publications

Poor diet quality is associated with immune aging in survivors of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia

Benmoussa, Kientega, Morel, Cardin, Bérard, Wajnberg, Valtchev, Blondin-Masse, Curnier, Krajinovic, Laverdière, Sinnett, Levy, Marcoux, Rodier, Marcil in Cancer research (2022)

FCA went (multi-) relational, but does it make any difference?

Wajnberg, Valtchev, Lezoche, Blondin-Massé, Panetto at CEUR-WS (2021)

Mining heterogeneous associations from pediatric cancer data by Relational Concept Analysis

Wajnberg, Valtchev, Blondin-Massé, Benmoussa, Krajinovic, Laverdiere, Levy, Sinnett, Marcil **at** ICDM-W (2020)

The Dictionary Game: Toward a Characterization of Lexical Primitives Using Graph Theory and Relational Concept Analysis

Wajnberg, Poulin, Massé, Valtchev at Cognitive (2020)

Tutorial Donereca

Wajnberg, Valtchev at JOWO (2019)

Mining process factor causality links with multi-relational associations Wajnberg, Valtchev, Lezoche, Panetto, Blondin Massé at Knowledge Capture (2019)

Concept analysis-based association mining from linked data: A case in industrial decision making

Wajnberg, Valtchev, Lezoche, Panetto and Blondin-Massé. at DAO-SI (2019)

Semantic interoperability of large systems through a formal method: Relational Concept Analysis

Wajnberg, Lezoche, Blondin-Massé, Valtchev, Panetto and Tyvaert at IFAC (2018)